(logo reverberates)
- So we're really rolling now.
We've got our enemy that
rolls towards our player,
and it's not moving at
an incredibly fast speed.
So, one real quick thing
that we're gonna do,
is we're just going to
clean up some of our code.
So, in our update function
we have this really
long line of code here,
so we're actually just going
to clean this up a little bit
by using one variable.
Now, because in our update
function is the only place
that we're really going to be calculating
the position of the player
against the current position of the enemy,
this is where we're going
to create our variable
so that we don't need it anywhere else.
So we're going to create a Vector3,
because we're taking in
two different positions,
our player and our current transform.
We'll call this Vector3 the lookDirection.
So this'll actually be the direction
that the enemy will be moving towards.
We're going to set this,
and we're actually just
gonna take this line of code.
We can cut it and paste it,
and then we'll close off with a semicolon.
Now, the reason why we
keep our equation here
still in parenthesis,
is just so that we can
use the .normalized,
so that way we can apply
our normalized vector
on to the final vector that
comes out of this position here.
So now that we have that in our AddForce,
we can just put lookDirection.
And when we save, if we test our game,
you can see that the enemy is still moving
at the same speed towards the player.
So, now it's your turn.
In your Update method,
you're going to create
a new Vector3 variable for the direction
that our enemy's going to move towards.
You're going to take the equation
that we had in our AddForce
for the player's position
minus the enemy's current position.
And then you're gonna
normalize that entire vector,
so that way it doesn't
increase in magnitude
the farther the two objects are away.
And then, your lookDirection
you'll just add
into your AddForce.
Now it's your turn.
(logo reverberates)